Stasny Family papers, Inclusive: 1888-1975, Bulk: 1913-1941
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Stasny Family papers
Inclusive: 1888-1975, Bulk: 1913-1941
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
2155
Stasny, Frank Daniel
2 document boxes
The Stasny Family Papers include correspondence to the Stansys, financial and legal records, collected materials, and photographs.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Frank Daniel Stasny was born on 1895 April 6 in Kovar, Texas. His parents, Martin Stasny and Rosina Kovar Stasny, were both born in the Czech Republic. Stasny was a teacher at the Stasny School in the Kovar community. Frank and his wife Agnes, had no children but adopted and reared seven children. Census records list his profession as a farmer in Bastrop County. He held an office in the Slovansk Podporujici Jednota Statu Texas, a Texas Czechs fraternal benefit society that worked to reinforce a sense of Czech cultural identity. He died on 1977 March 20 and is buried in the Kovar Catholic Cemetery in Bastrop County, Texas.
Scope and Content
The Stasny Family papers consist of correspondences, financial ledgers, tax receipts, land deeds, oil and gas land leases, farm maps, farm plans, family photographs, postcards, school booklets, and cufflinks. The majority of the correspondences are hand written letters from Frank Stasny to his family members Julia, Will, and Jim Stasny. A small portion of the correspondences are in Czech. The Stasny family was a farming family and the majority of the land deeds pertain to their farming lands, including maps and plans. The collection includes family photographs of Mr. and Mrs. Frank Stasny along with photographs of unidentified people.
The contents are dated from 1888 to 1975, however the bulk of the contents are from 1913-1941.
Arrangement
The Stasny Family Papers collection is divided into two boxes. The collection was previously separated into folders based on material type. The collection is now arranged into four series: correspondences, financial and legal documents, photographs, and general.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 2155. Acquired 1977-08-28
Related Resources
Related references
Find A Grave, Inc. “Frank Daniel Stasny.” Memorial #47177530. Databases. Accessed 2019 November 10.
Krusekopf, Henry. “Kovar Remembered.” Smithville Texas History. 1987 November 26. Accessed 2019 November 10.
Marks, Paula Mitchell. "Kovar, TX." Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2019 November 10.
U.S. Bureau of the Census. 1930 United States Census, s.v. “Frank Stasny,” Precinct 2, Bastrop County, Texas. Heritage Quest Online, Accessed 2019 November 10.
Index Terms
Subjects
Agriculture -- Texas.; Czech Americans -- Texas -- Biography.
Genres
Account books.; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Legal instruments.; Photographs.
- Correspondence, 1913-1941; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains postcards and correspondences.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Postcards
  - Correspondences, 1913-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Financial and Legal Documents, 1888-1975; 2
  This series contains financial ledgers, general ledgers, receipts, contracts, deeds, leases, and land maps.
  - Financial ledgers, 1912-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Financial ledgers, 1913-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial ledger, 1908-1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ledger, 1958-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Receipts, 1895-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Receipts, 1921-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Contracts, 1888-1907 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contracts, 1909-1911 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Land documents, 1924-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Land maps, 1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- General, 1918; 3
  This series contains school notebooks, sympathy cards, pamphlets, award ribbons, cufflinks and a tobacco bag.
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Printed materials, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Artifacts, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Photographs, undated; 4
  This series contains photographs of the Stasny family and other unidentified people.
  Photographic print
  - Stasny Family Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mrs. Birdie Moegle Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified Men photographs (1 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified Men photographs (2 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified Women photographs (1 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Women photographs (2 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Women photographs (3 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Children photographs (1 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified Children photographs (2 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified Children photographs (3 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (1 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (2 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (3 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (4 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (5 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (6 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (7 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (8 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified Groups photographs (9 of 9), undated (Box 2, Folder 14)